# **ANDREW NOONAN**

215-292-5083 | andrew@noonan.cc

#### **SUMMARY**

Over 10 years of experience as an engineer, manager, and tech lead. Technical lead for large scale projects, working with cross functional teams both internal and external. Interested in capitalizing on my diverse experience to build and execute a product roadmap.

#### **SKILLS**

Software Engineering, Systems Architecture, API Design Product Management & Development, Project Management Java, Python, Node, C++, SQL, Cassandra, Redis, Lucene

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

NOVEMBER 2015 - JANUARY 2020

# Technical Lead Manager, Senior Partner Engineer, Uber

- Technical lead and system architect for Uber Money's banking product
- Lead engineering effort for \$3.7 Billion merger with Yandex.taxi in Russia
- Delivered react native clone of the Uber rider app in Russia to ~10 million users in under 10 months managing a cross functional team of internal and external stakeholders
- Designed and launched Uber/Google Maps integration to ~5 million riders
- Co-designed Google OpenID authentication protocol for use in integration

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

#### Head of Partner Engineering, Asana

- Fostered relationships with large organizations such as Slack and Atlassian to extend Asana's product reach through integrations
- Prioritized engineering and product asks from external partners
- Worked closely with CEO and other leaders in the company to prioritize internal and external product roadmaps to enable integrations

MAY 2014 - JANUARY 2015

#### Senior Partner Engineer, Twitter

- Helped design and launch mobile attribution platform for Twitter ads
- Managed technical relationships with all major industry mobile ads tracking platforms

DECEMBER 2011 - MAY 2014

# Software Engineer, Head of Partner Engineering, Gnip

- Developed business plan for and launched Partner Engineering team at Gnip
- Increased revenue of strategic partnerships through technical optimizations and tighter product feedback loops
- Developed highly concurrent backend web applications in Java and RoR
- Designed and implemented geo location and language detection algorithms with >20,000 rps

### **Software Engineer,** Lockheed Martin

- Co-developed award winning geospatial functionality on a tactical display framework in Java
- Directed a team of developers through the refactoring of a group based permissioning system to control access to Java and C++ applications and back-end functions
- Engineered TCP/IP packet based communication between C++ and Java applications
- Held a Top Secret clearance from the United States Department of Defense

## **EDUCATION**

Graduated 2009

University of Colorado at Boulder- Boulder, Colorado Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Engineering major, Computer Engineering minor Engineering and Applied Science Dean's List Elected President of the Engineering School

Graduated 2005

William Penn Charter School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania High School Diploma, May 2005 Graduated with academic honors, AP Calculus, Physics, and Chemistry score 4/5